<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!--
Copyright (c) 2022, QIIME 2 development team.

Distributed under the terms of the Modified BSD License. (SPDX: BSD-3-Clause)
-->
<!--
This tool was automatically generated by:
    q2galaxy (version: 2022.2.0)
for:
    qiime2 (version: 2022.2.1)
-->
<tool name="qiime2 emperor plot" id="qiime2_emperor_plot" version="2022.2.0+q2galaxy.2022.2.0" profile="20.09" license="BSD-3-Clause">
    <description>Visualize and Interact with Principal Coordinates Analysis Plots</description>
    <requirements>
        <container type="docker">quay.io/qiime2/core:2022.2</container>
    </requirements>
    <version_command>q2galaxy version emperor</version_command>
    <command detect_errors="aggressive">q2galaxy run emperor plot '$inputs'</command>
    <configfiles>
        <inputs name="inputs" data_style="paths"/>
    </configfiles>
    <inputs>
        <param name="pcoa" type="data" format="qza" label="pcoa: PCoAResults" help="[required]  The principal coordinates matrix to be plotted.">
            <options options_filter_attribute="metadata.semantic_type">
                <filter type="add_value" value="PCoAResults"/>
            </options>
            <validator type="expression" message="Incompatible type">hasattr(value.metadata, "semantic_type") and value.metadata.semantic_type in {'PCoAResults'}</validator>
        </param>
        <repeat name="metadata" min="1" help="[required]  The sample metadata." title="metadata: Metadata">
            <conditional name="__q2galaxy__GUI__conditional__metadata__">
                <param name="type" type="select" label="metadata: Metadata">
                    <option value="tsv" selected="true">Metadata from TSV</option>
                    <option value="qza">Metadata from Artifact</option>
                </param>
                <when value="tsv">
                    <param name="source" type="data" format="tabular,qiime2.tabular" label="Metadata Source"/>
                </when>
                <when value="qza">
                    <param name="source" type="data" format="qza" label="Metadata Source"/>
                </when>
            </conditional>
        </repeat>
        <section name="__q2galaxy__GUI__section__extra_opts__" title="Click here for additional options">
            <repeat name="custom_axes" help="[optional]  Numeric sample metadata columns that should be included as axes in the Emperor plot." title="custom_axes: List[Str]">
                <param name="element" type="text" label="element: Str" help="[required]">
                    <sanitizer>
                        <valid initial="string.printable"/>
                    </sanitizer>
                    <validator type="expression" message="Please verify this parameter.">value is not None and len(value) &gt; 0</validator>
                </param>
            </repeat>
            <param name="ignore_missing_samples" type="boolean" truevalue="__q2galaxy__::literal::True" falsevalue="__q2galaxy__::literal::False" label="ignore_missing_samples: Bool" help="[default: No]  This will suppress the error raised when the coordinates matrix contains samples that are not present in the metadata. Samples without metadata are included by setting all metadata values to: &quot;This sample has no metadata&quot;. This flag is only applied if at least one sample is present in both the coordinates matrix and the metadata."/>
            <param name="ignore_pcoa_features" type="boolean" truevalue="__q2galaxy__::literal::True" falsevalue="__q2galaxy__::literal::False" label="ignore_pcoa_features: Bool" help="[default: No]  Biplot arrows cannot be visualized using this method. If you want to visualize biplot arrows use the `biplot` method. Enabling this setting will ignore any PCoA features that are present, otherwise, if PCoA features are detected an error will be raised."/>
        </section>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <data name="visualization" format="qzv" label="${tool.id} on ${on_string}: visualization.qzv" from_work_dir="visualization.qzv"/>
    </outputs>
    <tests/>
    <help>
QIIME 2: emperor plot
=====================
Visualize and Interact with Principal Coordinates Analysis Plots


Outputs:
--------
:visualization.qzv: &lt;no description&gt;

|  

Description:
------------
Generates an interactive ordination plot where the user can visually integrate sample metadata.


|  

</help>
    <citations>
        <citation type="bibtex">@article{cite1,
 author = {Vázquez-Baeza, Yoshiki and Pirrung, Meg and Gonzalez, Antonio and Knight, Rob},
 doi = {10.1186/2047-217X-2-16},
 journal = {Gigascience},
 number = {1},
 pages = {16},
 publisher = {BioMed Central},
 title = {EMPeror: a tool for visualizing high-throughput microbial community data},
 volume = {2},
 year = {2013}
}

</citation>
        <citation type="bibtex">@article{cite2,
 author = {Vázquez-Baeza, Yoshiki and Gonzalez, Antonio and Smarr, Larry and McDonald, Daniel and Morton, James T and Navas-Molina, Jose A and Knight, Rob},
 doi = {10.1016/j.chom.2016.12.009},
 journal = {Cell host &amp; microbe},
 number = {1},
 pages = {7--10},
 publisher = {Elsevier},
 title = {Bringing the dynamic microbiome to life with animations},
 volume = {21},
 year = {2017}
}

</citation>
        <citation type="bibtex">@article{cite3,
 author = {Bolyen, Evan and Rideout, Jai Ram and Dillon, Matthew R. and Bokulich, Nicholas A. and Abnet, Christian C. and Al-Ghalith, Gabriel A. and Alexander, Harriet and Alm, Eric J. and Arumugam, Manimozhiyan and Asnicar, Francesco and Bai, Yang and Bisanz, Jordan E. and Bittinger, Kyle and Brejnrod, Asker and Brislawn, Colin J. and Brown, C. Titus and Callahan, Benjamin J. and Caraballo-Rodríguez, Andrés Mauricio and Chase, John and Cope, Emily K. and Da Silva, Ricardo and Diener, Christian and Dorrestein, Pieter C. and Douglas, Gavin M. and Durall, Daniel M. and Duvallet, Claire and Edwardson, Christian F. and Ernst, Madeleine and Estaki, Mehrbod and Fouquier, Jennifer and Gauglitz, Julia M. and Gibbons, Sean M. and Gibson, Deanna L. and Gonzalez, Antonio and Gorlick, Kestrel and Guo, Jiarong and Hillmann, Benjamin and Holmes, Susan and Holste, Hannes and Huttenhower, Curtis and Huttley, Gavin A. and Janssen, Stefan and Jarmusch, Alan K. and Jiang, Lingjing and Kaehler, Benjamin D. and Kang, Kyo Bin and Keefe, Christopher R. and Keim, Paul and Kelley, Scott T. and Knights, Dan and Koester, Irina and Kosciolek, Tomasz and Kreps, Jorden and Langille, Morgan G. I. and Lee, Joslynn and Ley, Ruth and Liu, Yong-Xin and Loftfield, Erikka and Lozupone, Catherine and Maher, Massoud and Marotz, Clarisse and Martin, Bryan D. and McDonald, Daniel and McIver, Lauren J. and Melnik, Alexey V. and Metcalf, Jessica L. and Morgan, Sydney C. and Morton, Jamie T. and Naimey, Ahmad Turan and Navas-Molina, Jose A. and Nothias, Louis Felix and Orchanian, Stephanie B. and Pearson, Talima and Peoples, Samuel L. and Petras, Daniel and Preuss, Mary Lai and Pruesse, Elmar and Rasmussen, Lasse Buur and Rivers, Adam and Robeson, Michael S. and Rosenthal, Patrick and Segata, Nicola and Shaffer, Michael and Shiffer, Arron and Sinha, Rashmi and Song, Se Jin and Spear, John R. and Swafford, Austin D. and Thompson, Luke R. and Torres, Pedro J. and Trinh, Pauline and Tripathi, Anupriya and Turnbaugh, Peter J. and Ul-Hasan, Sabah and van der Hooft, Justin J. J. and Vargas, Fernando and Vázquez-Baeza, Yoshiki and Vogtmann, Emily and von Hippel, Max and Walters, William and Wan, Yunhu and Wang, Mingxun and Warren, Jonathan and Weber, Kyle C. and Williamson, Charles H. D. and Willis, Amy D. and Xu, Zhenjiang Zech and Zaneveld, Jesse R. and Zhang, Yilong and Zhu, Qiyun and Knight, Rob and Caporaso, J. Gregory},
 doi = {10.1038/s41587-019-0209-9},
 issn = {1546-1696},
 journal = {Nature Biotechnology},
 number = {8},
 pages = {852-857},
 title = {Reproducible, interactive, scalable and extensible microbiome data science using QIIME 2},
 url = {https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-019-0209-9},
 volume = {37},
 year = {2019}
}

</citation>
    </citations>
</tool>
