<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!--
Copyright (c) 2022, QIIME 2 development team.

Distributed under the terms of the Modified BSD License. (SPDX: BSD-3-Clause)
-->
<!--
This tool was automatically generated by:
    q2galaxy (version: 2022.2.0)
for:
    qiime2 (version: 2022.2.1)
-->
<tool name="qiime2 vsearch cluster-features-open-reference" id="qiime2_vsearch_cluster-features-open-reference" version="2022.2.0+q2galaxy.2022.2.0" profile="20.09" license="BSD-3-Clause">
    <description>Open-reference clustering of features.</description>
    <requirements>
        <container type="docker">quay.io/qiime2/core:2022.2</container>
    </requirements>
    <version_command>q2galaxy version vsearch</version_command>
    <command detect_errors="aggressive">q2galaxy run vsearch cluster_features_open_reference '$inputs'</command>
    <configfiles>
        <inputs name="inputs" data_style="paths"/>
    </configfiles>
    <inputs>
        <param name="sequences" type="data" format="qza" label="sequences: FeatureData[Sequence]" help="[required]  The sequences corresponding to the features in table.">
            <options options_filter_attribute="metadata.semantic_type">
                <filter type="add_value" value="FeatureData[Sequence]"/>
            </options>
            <validator type="expression" message="Incompatible type">hasattr(value.metadata, "semantic_type") and value.metadata.semantic_type in {'FeatureData[Sequence]'}</validator>
        </param>
        <param name="table" type="data" format="qza" label="table: FeatureTable[Frequency]" help="[required]  The feature table to be clustered.">
            <options options_filter_attribute="metadata.semantic_type">
                <filter type="add_value" value="FeatureTable[Frequency]"/>
            </options>
            <validator type="expression" message="Incompatible type">hasattr(value.metadata, "semantic_type") and value.metadata.semantic_type in {'FeatureTable[Frequency]'}</validator>
        </param>
        <param name="reference_sequences" type="data" format="qza" label="reference_sequences: FeatureData[Sequence]" help="[required]  The sequences to use as cluster centroids.">
            <options options_filter_attribute="metadata.semantic_type">
                <filter type="add_value" value="FeatureData[Sequence]"/>
            </options>
            <validator type="expression" message="Incompatible type">hasattr(value.metadata, "semantic_type") and value.metadata.semantic_type in {'FeatureData[Sequence]'}</validator>
        </param>
        <param name="perc_identity" type="float" min="1e-06" max="1" value="" label="perc_identity: Float % Range(0, 1, inclusive_start=False, inclusive_end=True)" help="[required]  The percent identity at which clustering should be performed. This parameter maps to vsearch's --id parameter."/>
        <section name="__q2galaxy__GUI__section__extra_opts__" title="Click here for additional options">
            <param name="strand" type="select" label="strand: Str % Choices('plus', 'both')" help="[default: 'plus']  Search plus (i.e., forward) or both (i.e., forward and reverse complement) strands." display="radio">
                <option value="plus" selected="true">plus</option>
                <option value="both">both</option>
            </param>
            <param name="threads" type="integer" min="0" max="256" value="1" label="threads: Int % Range(0, 256, inclusive_end=True)" help="[default: 1]  The number of threads to use for computation. Passing 0 will launch one thread per CPU core."/>
        </section>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <data name="clustered_table" format="qza" label="${tool.id} on ${on_string}: clustered_table.qza" from_work_dir="clustered_table.qza"/>
        <data name="clustered_sequences" format="qza" label="${tool.id} on ${on_string}: clustered_sequences.qza" from_work_dir="clustered_sequences.qza"/>
        <data name="new_reference_sequences" format="qza" label="${tool.id} on ${on_string}: new_reference_sequences.qza" from_work_dir="new_reference_sequences.qza"/>
    </outputs>
    <tests/>
    <help>
QIIME 2: vsearch cluster-features-open-reference
================================================
Open-reference clustering of features.


Outputs:
--------
:clustered_table.qza: The table following clustering of features.
:clustered_sequences.qza: Sequences representing clustered features.
:new_reference_sequences.qza: The new reference sequences. This can be used for subsequent runs of open-reference clustering for consistent definitions of features across open-reference feature tables.

|  

Description:
------------
Given a feature table and the associated feature sequences, cluster the features against a reference database based on user-specified percent identity threshold of their sequences. Any sequences that don't match are then clustered de novo. This is not a general-purpose clustering method, but rather is intended to be used for clustering the results of quality-filtering/dereplication methods, such as DADA2, or for re-clustering a FeatureTable at a lower percent identity than it was originally clustered at. When a group of features in the input table are clustered into a single feature, the frequency of that single feature in a given sample is the sum of the frequencies of the features that were clustered in that sample. Feature identifiers will be inherited from the centroid feature of each cluster. For features that match a reference sequence, the centroid feature is that reference sequence, so its identifier will become the feature identifier. The clustered_sequences result will contain feature representative sequences that are derived from the sequences input for all features in clustered_table. This will always be the most abundant sequence in the cluster. The new_reference_sequences result will contain the entire reference database, plus feature representative sequences for any de novo features. This is intended to be used as a reference database in subsequent iterations of cluster_features_open_reference, if applicable. See the vsearch documentation for details on how sequence clustering is performed.


|  

</help>
    <citations>
        <citation type="bibtex">@article{cite1,
 author = {Rideout, Jai Ram and He, Yan and Navas-Molina, Jose A. and Walters, William A. and Ursell, Luke K. and Gibbons, Sean M. and Chase, John and McDonald, Daniel and Gonzalez, Antonio and Robbins-Pianka, Adam and Clemente, Jose C. and Gilbert, Jack A. and Huse, Susan M. and Zhou, Hong-Wei and Knight, Rob and Caporaso, J. Gregory},
 doi = {10.7717/peerj.545},
 journal = {PeerJ},
 pages = {e545},
 publisher = {PeerJ Inc.},
 title = {Subsampled open-reference clustering creates consistent, comprehensive OTU definitions and scales to billions of sequences},
 volume = {2},
 year = {2014}
}

</citation>
        <citation type="bibtex">@article{cite2,
 author = {Rognes, Torbjørn and Flouri, Tomáš and Nichols, Ben and Quince, Christopher and Mahé, Frédéric},
 doi = {10.7717/peerj.2584},
 journal = {PeerJ},
 pages = {e2584},
 publisher = {PeerJ Inc.},
 title = {VSEARCH: a versatile open source tool for metagenomics},
 volume = {4},
 year = {2016}
}

</citation>
        <citation type="bibtex">@article{cite3,
 author = {Bolyen, Evan and Rideout, Jai Ram and Dillon, Matthew R. and Bokulich, Nicholas A. and Abnet, Christian C. and Al-Ghalith, Gabriel A. and Alexander, Harriet and Alm, Eric J. and Arumugam, Manimozhiyan and Asnicar, Francesco and Bai, Yang and Bisanz, Jordan E. and Bittinger, Kyle and Brejnrod, Asker and Brislawn, Colin J. and Brown, C. Titus and Callahan, Benjamin J. and Caraballo-Rodríguez, Andrés Mauricio and Chase, John and Cope, Emily K. and Da Silva, Ricardo and Diener, Christian and Dorrestein, Pieter C. and Douglas, Gavin M. and Durall, Daniel M. and Duvallet, Claire and Edwardson, Christian F. and Ernst, Madeleine and Estaki, Mehrbod and Fouquier, Jennifer and Gauglitz, Julia M. and Gibbons, Sean M. and Gibson, Deanna L. and Gonzalez, Antonio and Gorlick, Kestrel and Guo, Jiarong and Hillmann, Benjamin and Holmes, Susan and Holste, Hannes and Huttenhower, Curtis and Huttley, Gavin A. and Janssen, Stefan and Jarmusch, Alan K. and Jiang, Lingjing and Kaehler, Benjamin D. and Kang, Kyo Bin and Keefe, Christopher R. and Keim, Paul and Kelley, Scott T. and Knights, Dan and Koester, Irina and Kosciolek, Tomasz and Kreps, Jorden and Langille, Morgan G. I. and Lee, Joslynn and Ley, Ruth and Liu, Yong-Xin and Loftfield, Erikka and Lozupone, Catherine and Maher, Massoud and Marotz, Clarisse and Martin, Bryan D. and McDonald, Daniel and McIver, Lauren J. and Melnik, Alexey V. and Metcalf, Jessica L. and Morgan, Sydney C. and Morton, Jamie T. and Naimey, Ahmad Turan and Navas-Molina, Jose A. and Nothias, Louis Felix and Orchanian, Stephanie B. and Pearson, Talima and Peoples, Samuel L. and Petras, Daniel and Preuss, Mary Lai and Pruesse, Elmar and Rasmussen, Lasse Buur and Rivers, Adam and Robeson, Michael S. and Rosenthal, Patrick and Segata, Nicola and Shaffer, Michael and Shiffer, Arron and Sinha, Rashmi and Song, Se Jin and Spear, John R. and Swafford, Austin D. and Thompson, Luke R. and Torres, Pedro J. and Trinh, Pauline and Tripathi, Anupriya and Turnbaugh, Peter J. and Ul-Hasan, Sabah and van der Hooft, Justin J. J. and Vargas, Fernando and Vázquez-Baeza, Yoshiki and Vogtmann, Emily and von Hippel, Max and Walters, William and Wan, Yunhu and Wang, Mingxun and Warren, Jonathan and Weber, Kyle C. and Williamson, Charles H. D. and Willis, Amy D. and Xu, Zhenjiang Zech and Zaneveld, Jesse R. and Zhang, Yilong and Zhu, Qiyun and Knight, Rob and Caporaso, J. Gregory},
 doi = {10.1038/s41587-019-0209-9},
 issn = {1546-1696},
 journal = {Nature Biotechnology},
 number = {8},
 pages = {852-857},
 title = {Reproducible, interactive, scalable and extensible microbiome data science using QIIME 2},
 url = {https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-019-0209-9},
 volume = {37},
 year = {2019}
}

</citation>
    </citations>
</tool>
